tntexpress.com.au 2012-05-24

# 

                                      TNT Australia Pty Limited
                                    Privacy Policy & Guidelines
Background to TNT Australia Pty Limited’s Privacy Policy and Guidelines
On 21 December 2001 the Privacy (Public Sector) Amendment Act 2000 (“Privacy Act”) came into
force in Australia to regulate the way in which corporations deal with personal information. TNT
Australia Pty Limited (“TNT”) is required to comply with the Privacy Act.
TNT has established this Privacy Policy & Guidelines to implement a system for TNT and its staff to
manage personal information.
Please feel free to call the TNT Legal Department on (02) 8304 8016 or tie line 628016 if you have
any queries or are uncertain of any issues that are contained in this document.
What is personal information?
“Personal information” is any information that can identify an individual or allow someone to make
enquiries to identify an individual. Some examples of personal information such as names, addresses,
telephone and fax numbers, email addresses and so on.
The Privacy Act excludes our employees’ personal information but does not exclude information on
past and prospective employees or any contractors or sub-contractors.
TNT’s Policy based on the Privacy Principles outlined in the Privacy Act is outlined
below:
1.          Collection
            TNT may collect personal information needed to fulfil its legitimate functions
            (“TNT’s Functions”). TNT will only collect personal information by lawful and
            fair means and not in an unreasonably intrusive way.
            We may collect information which is necessary for us to fulfil the TNT Functions, for
            example, contact names and addresses for the efficient and timely delivery of freight in our
            express freight, logistics and mail businesses.
            We will only collect this information lawfully and during the course of our normal business
            transactions.
2.          Use and Disclosure
            TNT may use and disclose personal information for activities associated with the
            TNT Functions (“secondary purpose”).
            TNT will only collect personal information for a purpose other than for TNT’s Functions if:
            (a)    the secondary purpose is related to the TNT Functions and if individuals would
                   reasonably expect us to collect that information; or
AU-LEG (L) – RG – 002                             1 of 6                                         Version: 1.0
Approved by: Chris Stannage                                                              Issue Date: 13/07/07
Title: Director Legal Services

                                       TNT Australia Pty Limited
                                      Privacy Policy & Guidelines
            (b)    if the individual has consented; or
            (c)    if we use that information for direct marketing and it has not been practicable for us to
                   get your consent before using that information.
            Usually, we will not use or disclose personal information unless it is part of TNT’s Functions.
            For example, we need to disclose this information to contract drivers or agents when they
            deliver freight to a contact name and address.
            Sometimes, however, we will need to disclose personal information to a third party for a
            purpose directly related to the TNT Functions. For example, we provide all of our
            consignment notes to a third party for imaging. In instances such as this, we will ensure that
            a confidentiality agreement is in place with all of our suppliers and will request an
            acknowledgment from them that they will comply with the Privacy Act and National Privacy
            Principles.
            In some instances, we will attempt to obtain consent to use or disclose personal information
            for secondary purposes such as direct marketing activities, however, sometimes this may not
            be practicable. In these circumstances, we recognise that some customers may not want us
            to use or disclose their personal information for this purpose and they should be free to
            inform us of this fact. Once a customer has notified us in writing that they wish to be
            removed from our direct marketing database, we will remove them from our database as
            soon as possible.
            We recognise that an individual may wish to be removed from our direct marketing database
            or have his or her personal information deleted from our systems at any time.
3.          Data Quality
            We will take reasonable steps to make sure that the personal information we
            collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete and up to date.
            TNT updates much of the information we hold on the request of a customer. We rely
            heavily upon our customers notifying us when their information changes. However, from
            time to time we will “wash” our database to ensure the information we hold is correct.
            Some information is held on systems that are no longer in use but are still maintained by
            TNT. We will endeavour to assess these systems periodically and delete old or inaccurate
            information from these systems where possible.
4.          Data Security
            We will take reasonable steps to protect the personal information we hold from
            misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification, or disclosure.
            We have a secure computer and information management system and will do our utmost to
            ensure it is safe from unauthorised use. This means disabling access to former employees
            and having systems in place to protect personal information from unauthorised use.
AU-LEG (L) – RG – 002                              2 of 6                                            Version: 1.0
Approved by: Chris Stannage                                                                  Issue Date: 13/07/07
Title: Director Legal Services

                                    TNT Australia Pty Limited
                                   Privacy Policy & Guidelines
            We back up all electronic information on a regular basis and keep copies of this information
            on tapes and disks which are securely held.
            Only employees who need access to personal information are authorised to do so.
            We will ensure that all existing and new employees are given a copy of our Privacy Policy
            Statement, these Policy Guidelines and Policy Procedures.
            We will provide resources to all our employees to enable them to understand their
            obligations under the Privacy Act.
            We will ask our suppliers or contractors that have access to personal information held by
            TNT to execute a confidentiality agreement which will contain an acknowledgment that they
            are fully compliant with the Privacy Act.
            TNT’s existing policy on lost personal information will apply if such circumstances arise.
            We will take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify personal
            information if it is no longer needed.
            TNT updates much of the information we hold on the request of a customer. We rely
            heavily upon our customers notifying us when their information changes. From time to time
            we will continue to “wash” our database to ensure the information we hold is correct. We
            will delete or destroy information that is no longer needed for TNT Functions or secondary
            purposes.
            Some information is held on systems that are no longer used but still maintained by TNT.
            We will assess these systems periodically and delete old or inaccurate information where
            possible.
5.          Openness
            We will maintain a Privacy Policy Statement and these Privacy Guidelines
            setting out how we will manage personal information.
            We will provide a copy of our Privacy Policy Statement and Privacy Policy Guidelines to
            anyone who asks for a copy of them.
            If requested, we will take reasonable steps to let any individual know, generally,
            what sort of personal information we hold, for what purpose, and how we collect,
            hold, use and disclose that information.
            All requests should be made to us in writing, setting out what the individual would like to
            know about what personal information we are holding. This request must be referred to
            Susan Davies, Director Administration, Customer Service and Human Resources. Once she
            receives this written request, she will arrange to let the individual know, generally what sort
AU-LEG (L) – RG – 002                            3 of 6                                             Version: 1.0
Approved by: Chris Stannage                                                                 Issue Date: 13/07/07
Title: Director Legal Services

                                        TNT Australia Pty Limited
                                      Privacy Policy & Guidelines
            of personal information we hold, for what purpose and how we collect, hold, use and
            disclose that information.
            We will aim to answer all requests within one month of receipt of the request. However, in
            some circumstances, it may not be practicable to do so. If this is the case, we will indicate
            how long it might take us to furnish the request.
            TNT may charge a reasonable fee for the provision of this service or may pass on to the
            individual requesting the information any fee charged to TNT for this service.
6.         Access and Correction
           We will provide an individual with access to their personal information upon
           written request. Exceptions to this are outlined below.
           The exceptions to this are where:
            (a)        providing access to the information will threaten the life, health or privacy of
                       another individual;
            (b)        the request is frivolous or vexatious;
            (c)        the information relates to existing or anticipated legal proceedings between us and
                       the individual and the information would not normally be discoverable;
            (d)        providing access would reveal our intentions in negotiations with the individual and
                       might prejudice those negotiations;
            (e)        providing access would be unlawful;
            (f)        denying access is required by law; or
            (g)        providing access could threaten the privacy of other individuals;
            (h)        providing access may prejudice a lawful investigation, the enforcement of laws,
                       protection of public revenue or the preparation for court proceedings; or
            (i)        if the provision of this information threatens the security of Australia.
            Once we receive a written request for access to or copies of personal information held by
            us, it must be directed to Susan Davies, Director Administration, Customer Service and
            Human Resources. Susan Davies will then arrange to assess the request, subject to the
            provisions of the Privacy Act.
            Susan Davies will arrange to advise the requesting party what information we are holding and
            how much, if anything, it will cost to retrieve the information. Any charges for access to or
            copies of information will not be excessive. We may merely pass on costs charged to us by
            a supplier. For example, our supplier of imaging services may charge us to retrieve
            information. In these circumstances, we will pass on this cost to the individual requesting
            the information.
            Once we have provided an individual with access to or copies of their personal information
            and that individual is able to establish that the information is inaccurate, incomplete or out of
            date, or they object to it in some other way, we will correct the information. If we disagree
AU-LEG (L) – RG – 002                                 4 of 6                                             Version: 1.0
Approved by: Chris Stannage                                                                      Issue Date: 13/07/07
Title: Director Legal Services

                                    TNT Australia Pty Limited
                                   Privacy Policy & Guidelines
            with the individual about whether the information is accurate or the basis upon which they
            object to us holding the information, we will try to resolve the matter directly with them.
            If we cannot resolve the matter we will refer it to the Privacy Commissioner for a
            determination.
            TNT will give written reasons for our refusal to provide correction or access to the personal
            information.
7.         Identifiers
            TNT will not require or use any identifying information.
            “Identifying information” includes Medicare numbers, tax file numbers, pension numbers or
            other identifiers as defined in the Privacy Act. Although TNT does not collect and store
            identifying information we may transport such information for our customers.
            Any identifying information being transported for our customers must be sealed in an
            envelope or appropriate container by the customer and must not be opened by TNT staff
            except where it is necessary to facilitate delivery of the consignment. If it is necessary to
            open the sealed container the TNT staff member must reseal the container and keep the
            information confidential.
            One exception to this policy is where TNT as required by law, may collect the tax file
            number of contracted staff and pass it on to TNT Group Retirement Fund or the Australian
            Tax Office.
8.          Anonymity
            Where lawful and practicable, individuals may enter into transactions with us
            anonymously.
            Where we are able to, we will allow customers to deal with us anonymously. In most cases
            where we are delivering freight, we will need contact names, addresses and telephone
            numbers, so often this may not be possible. However, if a potential customer wants a quote
            and does not want to be identified, we may ask for a written request for a quote on the
            letterhead of the company requesting the quote and will not need any personal information
            from that individual.
9.          Transborder data flows
            We will not disclose your personal information except as required to perform TNT
            Functions or if required to do so by any other Commonwealth, State or Territory law.
AU-LEG (L) – RG – 002                            5 of 6                                             Version: 1.0
Approved by: Chris Stannage                                                                 Issue Date: 13/07/07
Title: Director Legal Services

                                     TNT Australia Pty Limited
                                   Privacy Policy & Guidelines
10.        Sensitive information
           TNT does not collect and store any sensitive information but it may transport such
           information for its customers. Any sensitive information must be sealed in an envelope or
           appropriate container by the customer and must not be opened by TNT staff except where
           it is necessary to facilitate delivery of the consignment. If it is necessary to open the sealed
           container the TNT staff member must reseal the container and keep the information
           confidential.
           If a TNT staff member opens or misplaces, whether accidentally or on purpose, a container
           of sensitive information this must be reported immediately to the TNT Legal Department.
            TNT’s existing policy on lost personal information will apply if such circumstances arise.
           Complaints or disputes to the Privacy Commissioner
            If anyone has a complaint regarding TNT’s use of their personal information they must be
            directed to Susan Davies, Director Administration, Customer Service and Human Resources
            on (02) 8304 8410.
            Susan Davies will attempt to resolve any complaints regarding privacy issues directly with the
            complainant but if unsuccessful Susan Davies will arrange to refer the complaint to the
            Privacy Commissioner for a determination.
AU-LEG (L) – RG – 002                              6 of 6                                            Version: 1.0
Approved by: Chris Stannage                                                                  Issue Date: 13/07/07
Title: Director Legal Services
